Emmet Family
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
[Mar 1897] - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Ethel Folsom works at Lazars; staying with Ally Haughton; Edith Stokes
[Mar 1897] - To: Lydia - From: Rosina Hubley Emmet - Subjects: to Fontainebleau; French sculptor Leon; Conkling; MacMonnies; Cousin Henry (James)
[1897] - To: Lydia - From: Rosina Hubley Emmet - Subjects: MacMonnies painted Rosina; posed in Paris for Whistler's portrait of Miss Peck; Whistler did critiques for Bay, Mary Clay and Mary Foote
Mar 29, 1897 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: plans for Oxford; Ethel Folsom; Paul Conkling; MacMonnies; Miss Scudder; Fontainebleau
[Mar 1897] - To: Rosie - From: Jane - Subject: Fontainebleau visit postponed; MacMonnies and French artist Bestant; Don Juan; Colome concert
[1897] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Stanford and Bessie White; MacMonnies; Eliza's engagement, glad it's not Alfred Booth; Mildred Howells; Bay; another month of Collin; Tonetti and Leon
[Apr 1897] - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: to Fontainebleau soon; the Chanlers; Richard Harding Davis; Johnny Howells shares flat with Mr. Rogers
[Apr 1897] - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: MacMonnies dinner; Susie; Mr. Rogers; Johnnie Howells; artist Mr. McEwan
Good Friday [1897] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Mr. Kevers (McEvers?); Bay's bike; Susie Clemens died last year; Bobby S. a year old
[Apr 1897] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Cornelia's baby; A. Phimister Proctor's baby; MacMonnies; Kevers (Mc Evers?); Champs Elysee vernissage; Paul Monuet; saw Mlle. Lara in Coquelin Cadet
[week after Easter, 1897] - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Champs Elysees vernissage; description of Champs de Mars exhibition; MacMonnies; Catlin girl; Trocadero concert; Miss Eustis' sister-in-law is Mrs. George Eustis; Eliza Wells; Peggy Newbold; Herters' party on May 14; Edith Carpenter married Everett Macy
[Spring 1897] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Uncle Dick's illness; MacMonnies' opinion of Scudder; girls will go straight to Southwold; Bay; Henry James; the Herters' ball; Collin afraid of Theresa Murphy; sorry to miss Eliza's wedding; the Diblees
Apr 16, 1897 - To: Lydia - From: Jane? - Subjects: Parsons party; Conkling; "grim Scudder"; MacMonnies admires Chanler; (drawings of a dress and party guest)
Apr 28, 1897 - To: Lydia - From: Addis - Subjects: thanks for the miniature; new McEvers arrival at New Rochelle; Griswold's cousin Julia Tucker died
[1897] - To: Julia - From: Bay - Subject: visited chateau Bellevue
[Apr 1897] - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: MacMonnies; costumes; uniform used by Saint-Gaudens for his Shaw Memorial
[May 1897] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Henry James; MacMonnies; Theresa Murphy; Mary Clarke; Joe Hunt; (drawing of costume for May 14 ball)
May 20, 1897 - To: Julia - From: Jane (in Giverny) - Subjects: in Giverny with MacMonnies; Conkling; Henry James; the Herters' ball
May 24, 1897 - To: Lydia - From: Jane? - Subjects: Bay's portrait of MacMonnies; MacMonnies adores Stevenson; artist M. Berthaut
May 28, 1897 - To: Lydia - From: Rosina - Subjects: MacMonnies; Sargent; to England June 12; Bay and Rosina to Paris again in winter
[Jun 1897] - To: Lydia - From: Rosina Hubley Emmet (in England) - Subjects: Bay and Rosina in Southwold, England; Jane seeing London with Dick Davis; Sargent to paint the Queen; Henry James; MacMonnies baby due in Nov.; MacMonnies invitation to Giverny; Pomeroy, sculptor friend of Sargent; Conkling
Jun 15, 1897 - To: Rosina Hubley Emmet - From: Frederick MacMonnies - Subject: MacMonnies in Giverny with Pomeroy
Jun 17, 1897 - To: Lydia? - From: Jane (in London for Jubilee) - Subjects: MacMonnies; Anthony Hope; Ethel Barrymore; Dick Davis; Grant's tomb; Justin McCarthy; Cissie Loftus; Fred Terry; Mamie Gosling; John Hay; Asquiths; Basil Temple Blackwood
[Jun 1897] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Sargent; Henry James; saw royalty; Cecilia Beaux; Florence Cross; Miss Hay; Dick Davis; Ethel Barrymore; Cecil Clark; Lyd at W. P.; Frank Parker (ex-Tory M.P.) is cousin of Joe Lawley
[Jun 1897] - To: Willy - From: Jane - Subjects: trying to avoid Jubilee; the Diblees; Mamie Gosling; Frank Parker; Kevers
[Jun 1897] - To: Julia - From: Jane (in Dunwich) - Subjects: with Mabel tonight; Aunt Elly and Gren; Bay, Leslie, and Anita; Rosina; Cornelia home on Saturday; Henry James' expected visit
[Jun 1897] - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Henry James; Jane's plans to sail; Rosina
Jul 26, 1897 - To: Lydia - From: Jane (at Surrenden, Pluckley, Kent) - Subjects: with Lewises since Saturday--friends of Redmond and Carew; Bronson Winthrop; Duggy Balfour; to see Henry James on Saturday
[Jul 1897] - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Conkling; MacMonnies; Henry James' book
Aug 3, 1897 - To: Julia - From: Jane (in Dunwich) - Subjects: Kevers and Maud Cunard; Bache Cunard; Nancy Cunard (a child); Leicester Fair on Wednesday; will sail the 14th on the St. Paul; Henry James didn't come on the 31st; Sargent lunching at Hans Crescent Hotel
Aug 6, 1897 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Henry James still expected; dancing bears performed in Dunwich; Lyd's thoughts of the major at the White House
Sep 10, 1897 - To: Lydia - From: Jane (in New York) - Subjects: Alida's baby; description of Bobby Sherwood
[Sep 1897] - To: Jane - From: Bay - Subjects: Stanford White; Jubilee; MacMonnies ("a composite of Mowbray, Willie, Temple, and Stevenson"); MacMonnies' studio; Conkling; Rosina; costume party; Anita von Hemert's daughter is 3 weeks old
[Sep 1897] - To: Lydia - From: Bay - Subjects: Mrs. McGinnis; Bay says Maria Kobbe wouldn't like a room at 96 Blvd. Montparnasse; Mary Foote
Oct 23, 1897 - To: Lydia - From: Bay and Leslie (96 Blvd. Montparnasse) - Subjects: money worries; Mrs. Griswold; Rolshoven's studio; Collin's class
[Oct 1897] - To: Lydia - From: Bay - Subject: don't raise funds; Rosina; Leslie
[Oct 1897] - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subjects: goodbye to Lydia; Jamey to visit in fall; Frank Kiefer's funeral; Navajoes
[Oct 1897] - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subject: Stanford White
Nov 19, 1897--------receipt for the Powel children miniature by Lydia
Nov 20, [1897] - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subjects: Mr. Powel's note; Jane to Yale game; visit of (Miss Thackera and Miss Fanny) from Fort Defiance who work with Navajoes
Nov 24, 1897 - To: Julia - From: Lydia (in Paris) - Subjects: arrival in England and Paris; Kob at Mrs. McGinnis'; Leslie; Mary Foote; Anita; Bay and Rose to a football game with Saint-Gaudens and MacMonnies Thanksgiving
[1897] - To: Lydia - From: Jane (in the United States) - Subjects: Bobby Sherwood; Billy at Rokeby liked Hester Lyttleton
[1897?] - To: July - From: Julia - Subjects: Jane wrote to Bessie Maginnis; Latin Quarter apartments are cheap; Lydia is going; length of Jane's stay
[Nov 1897] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Bessie White; Jack Beresford; the Gibsons; Stanford White; Powel miniature to Mr. Kobbe?
Dec 1, 1897 - To: Lydia - From: Posie - Subject: Bobby Sherwood
Dec 3, 1897 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Alida's baby; Cecilia Beaux in Boston; Jane to sketch Tichenor; Temple and W.J. Emmet to North Carolina
[Dec 1897] - To: Lydia (in Winchester, England) - From: Jane - Subjects: the League is rather awful; Johnny Weeks and Mrs. Henry Bowers; Mrs. Phelps; Jack Wells
Dec 4, 1897 - To: Lydia - From: Eleanor Temple Emmet (in New Rochelle) - Subjects: Alford Cooley; old Mrs. Iselin died last week
Dec 12, 1897 - To: Lydia - From: Posie - Subjects: in Boston last week, for Arthur's A.D. dinner; new subway; Shaw memorial; paintings by Abbey, Puvis de Chavannes and Sargent; Cecilia Beaux exhibition; Herbert Leeds; Mrs. Jack Gardner's story about Sargent at the exhibition
Dec 19, 1897 - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subjects: Kitty Keogh's baby; Zeb
Dec 20, [1897] - To: Lydia - From: Aunty - Subjects: Bobby; Charlotte Ogden's wedding
Dec 21, 1897 - To: Lydia - From: Cousin _____ Emmet - Subject: MacMonnies
Dec 21, 1897 - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subjects: Jane to the League with Cecilia Beaux; Robert Emmet miniature
Dec 26, 1897 - To: Lydia - From: Posie - Subjects: Bobby Sherwood; Daisy's Christmas party; Minnie Peabody is coming
[1897] - To: Lydia (96 Blvd. Montparnasse) - From: E.M. Morgan - Subjects: let him know about Sargent; Morgan may want portrait; MacMonnies
Jan 4, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Posie - Subjects: Richie Keogh? leaves; will see Coghlan in The Royal Box; Eleanor and Elizabeth to Redmond's lecture; split in Society of American Artists
Jan 4, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Mary Allen - Subject: re letter of introduction to Mme. Michel
Jan 4, 1898 - To: Julia - From: E. - Subjects: Annie Lawley; sorry not to have seen Dick again
Jan 11, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Bobby Sherwood's talking problems; Conkling to U.S.; Bobby Emmet going shooting with McKimbo; Van Vorst and Dandet's funerals; Jane to do Fred Tichenor's portrait
Jan 13, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subjects: Redmond; Henry Phelps; Chauncey Depew
Jan 16, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subjects: Conkling; MacMonnies; McKim
Jan 16, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: T.H.R. - Subjects: fancy dress ball; Shaw monument
Jan 18, [1898] - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subjects: Ella's new boy; Conkling
Jan 18, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: to museum to see the Sargent; Bay only likes MacMonnies' criticisms; saw Elizabeth Emmet; Paul Conkling to D.C.; McKimbo in the south
Jan 21, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subjects: Jane loves Prescott; Mrs. Phelps took care of Willy at Fort N.; Dev's baby; the Henschels
Jan 25, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Posie - Subjects: Bobby Sherwood; portrait for Rev. Van Dyke; Jack Beresford engagement; Miss Conkling's wedding; Emily Iselin
Jan 28, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subject: Stanford White
Jan 30, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subjects: Mr. Conkling; McKim
[Jan 1898] - To: Julia - From: Lydia (in France) - Subjects: Mrs. MacMonnies; Bay in Collin's class; Henry Clay (Bay's classmate); Sargent; MacMonnies; Bobby Sherwood
[Feb 1898] - To: Bay - From: Jane - Subjects: Henry James; Nell Kobbe in Hospital; Lulu Taft? and Lilly Brownell; League is rather awful; Yandell; Sargent; Bobby Sherwood
Feb 1, [1898] - To: Lydia - From: H.E. (?) (in New Rochelle) - Subjects: saw McKim; saw The Little Minister; Iselin-Beresford engagement; Mary Doolan
Feb 1, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: J.E.__.E. - Subjects: savings and loan business; Mrs. Perkins; John Leech and his art
Feb 3, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Eleanor Temple Emmet - Subject: Mr. Conkling
Feb 3, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Aunty - Subject: Bobby Sherwood; Posie's portrait of Rev. Van Dyke's dead son
Feb 6, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Posie - Subjects: Miss Kobbe; Bobby Sherwood; saw Mr. Chase at Delmonico's; Dreyfus case; Jane likes the League
Feb 9, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subjects: MacMonnies; Mr. Conkling in D.C.; Jane paints Sedgwick James' daughter; Jane works well at the League; Bobby Sherwood
Feb 10, 1898 - To: Julia - From: Lydia - Subjects: saw Cyrano; Dreyfus affair/Zola riots; Miss Herter's surprise dance; architects' ball on Monday; MacMonnies
Feb 13, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subjects: Bobby and Cynthia Sherwood's tantrums; Kitty's baby
Feb 14, 1898 - To: "American Mamma" - From: G. Hyde Clarke (at Hyde Hall, Cooperstown, N.Y.) - Subject: family activities
Feb 18, 1898 - To: Julia - From: Lydia (in France) - Subjects: sat next to Saint-Gaudens at dinner; met Dr. Schiff; Lilly Travers; costume ball at Vittio Academie; Edwin Lord Weekes; Mr. Bechtet; Charles Sprague Pearce; MacMonnies
[Feb 1898] - To: Julia - From: Cousin Julia - Subjects: Lydia in Paris; Dreyfus case; the Schiffs
Feb 20, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subjects: Stanford and Bessie White; Mr. Conkling; Ella's baby's christening
Feb 22, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Gov. Morris Phelps - Subjects: Emile Iselin married Jack Beresford yesterday; battleship The Maine
Feb 24, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subjects: Elizabeth Chanler; Posie and Arthur to D.C.; Bobby Sherwood; Zola; Bob Emmet away with McKim
[1898] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Elizabeth's secret; Zola trial; Conkling in D.C. and Annapolis
[1898] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: war; cousin Gunkel from Java
Mar 3, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subjects: Jane painting Sedgwick James girl; Zola and Dreyfus; Gen. Sherman's letter; Bob and Nelly dined with John Cadwallader
Mar 3, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Eleanor - Subject: battleship The Maine; Eleanor with Temple Emmet Carson, George Ferguson, and Lord Botelle
Mar 4, 1898 - To: Julia - From: Lydia (in France) - Subjects: Lizzie wants portrait of Alty Morgan by Sargent; Bay to London next week to visit Sargent; MacMonnies; Giverny cottage; Mary Foote; Leslie; Rose to U.S. in the fall
Mar 11, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subjects: Bobby Sherwood; McKim; Posie's Van Dyke portrait; Elizabeth Winthrop
Mar 13, 1898 - To: Miss Emmet - From: Frederick MacMonnies - Subject: re Saint-Gaudens
[Mar 1898] - To: ? - From: Posie(fragment) - Subjects: Mr. Conkling; MacMonnies and Saint-Gaudens
Mar 13, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subjects: war with Spain?; Posie and Arthur to D.C. tomorrow; Miss Crocker's money; Prince Poniatorvsky
[Mar 1898] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: MacMonnies and Saint-Gaudens; Aunty and Jane to D.C.; war preparations
Mar 15, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: the League, Mowbray, Cox; Sargent and Alty Morgan; Bobby Sherwood;Arthur and Posie to D.C. "to hold McKinley's topper"
Mar 16, 1898 - To: Arthur Sherwood - From: Theodore Roosevelt - Subject: invitation to see him
[1898] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subject: Marg to Cuba with Red Cross; Elizabeth Chanler married Jack Chapman
Mar 18, 1898 - To: Julia - From: Lydia - Subjects: Bessie McGinnis is ill; to Tours on June 10
Mar 18, 1898 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Mrs. McGinnis died, Mabel is helpless; MacMonnies is painting Clara Middleton; Bay in London painting Stanley Clarke; Giverny; MacMonnies; Dreyfus affair
Mar 18, 1898 - To: "Dear Madam" - From: Francis Carlin - Subject: formation of Society of Miniature Painters
Mar 18, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Annette E. von Munchhausen - Subject: invitation to visit
Mar 20, 1898 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: McGinnis funeral; MacMonnies; Whistler and Saint-Gaudens
Mar 25, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subjects: Posie back from D.C.; MacMonnies; Paul Conkling
Mar 25, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Fred Gary - Subject: pastels to offer
Mar 25, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Walter Rowlands - Subject: request for work
Mar 29, 1898 - To: Posie - From: Henry Van Dyke - Subject: thanks for son's portrait
Mar 30, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subjects: W.J. Emmet to Uncle Dick's; Aunty and Jane in D.C.; McKinley
[Apr 4,1898] - To: [Lydia] - From: Jane - Subjects: Bobby Sherwood; "the patron" (MacMonnies); Saint-Gaudens
Apr 4, 1898 - To: JuliaFrom:Lydia - Subjects: Dreyfus and Zola; war
Apr 10, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subjects: war; Alida and Temple visit; Willy Temple's article
Apr 12, 1898 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: visit to Saint-Gaudens' studio; MacMonnies; Bay's mother to Giverny in May; president's message
Apr 15, 1898 - To: Julia - From: Lydia - Subjects: war; Kobbe; Dr. Goode was wounded in Prussian war
Apr 15, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subjects: war preparation; Butler Duncan commands naval reserves
Apr 25, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Eleanor Temple Emmet - Subjects: war preparation; Bob in Chanler regiment
Apr 26, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subjects: Willy to D.C.; Bobby Sherwood
Apr 26, 1898 - To: Julia - From: Lydia (in France) - Subjects: Bay returns soon (from England); vernissage on Saturday; Mrs. MacMonnies to Giverny; Miss Kobbe; Lydia dislikes Conkling
Apr 26, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Arthur (Tower and Sherwood, 10 Wall St., N.Y.) - Subject: preparation for war
May 6, 1898 - To: Julia - From: Lydia - Subjects: Chanler regiment in Tampa; Aunt Elly and Gren to Giverny with Rosina
May 10, 1898 - To: Julia - From: Lydia - Subjects: Manila victory; money no longer a problem
[May 1898] - To: Lydia - From: Jane (in Port Tampa) - Subject: war preparation
[May 1898] - To: Lydia - From: Jane (in Port Tampa) - Subjects: Dick Davis; officers
Jun 3, [1898] - To: Lydia - From: Leslie? - Subjects: Giverny; Bay; MacMonnies; Mrs. MacMonnies' portrait of father; Mrs. Rechtill posing; Mrs. Fairchild; death of Hamilton Fish; Temple with Rough Riders; Bob stationed at Staten Island
Jun 7, 1898 - To: Julia - From: Jane (in Port Tampa) - Subjects: Rough Riders; Gen. Coppinger; Gen. Creighton Webb; Clara Barton; Temple tried to join Rough Riders, but Col. Roosevelt said he was a day too late
Jun 16, 1898 - To: Julia - From: Jane (in Port Tampa) - Subject: war preparation
[1898] - To: Posie - From: Julia - Subject: surrender of Santiago
Aug 5, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Maria Kobbe (in Weisbaden) - Subject: description of travels
Aug 8, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Maria Kobbe (in Munich) - Subject: description of travels
Sep 8, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Bay - Subjects: Giverny; Paul Conkling gone; MacMonnies' marriage
Sep 8, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Henry (in Eaglesmere, Pa.) - Subjects: Bay at Giverny; Henry paints his sister; modern art in London such as Whistler and Cecilia Beaux
Oct 4, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: George de C. Curtis (33 W 69th) - Subjects: sending a poem "The Curtis Workmen"
Nov 1, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: RosinaHubley Emmet - Subjects: MacMonnies; Henry Clay; Saint-Gaudens; Peggy Newbold; Stanford White; Whistler
Nov 23, 1898 - To: Jane - From: Lydia (on ship S.S. St. Paul) - Subjects: Fanny Stevens' husband; Whistler picture; Kobbe
[1898] - To: Lydia - From: Rosina Hubley Emmet - Subjects: Sargent; Saint-Gaudens; MacMonnies; Robert Chanler
Dec 7, 1898 - To: Dear Woman - From: Bay (1 rue Leopold Robert, Paris) - Subjects: Bay loves her studio; Henry Clay; Bay doing portrait of Rosina; Paul Barleigh; Ernest Slade; MacMonnies; Grace Deluze
Dec 19, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: George de C. Curtis - Subjects: sending toys for the children
[Dec 1898] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: MacMonnies; Bertha Hiliere; drawing of Arthur Jr. for Aunty
Dec 23, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Ma Porter's portrait; Elizabeth Winthrop christening; does Chanlers ask Patron's (MacMonnies) advice?; Nausen lecture
Dec 26, 1898 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subject: Lydia has a "bad combination" with MacMonnies; Bobby Sherwood's winter activities; (drawing of a tea strainer)
Dec 28, [1898?] - To: Miss Emmet - From: Royal Robbins (in New York) - Subject: thanks for painting
[1899] - To: Cynthia - From: Posie - Subject: Bobby Sherwood
Jan 6, 1899 - To: Lydia - From: Mary Foote - Subjects: loves new studio; MacMonnies baby; Lyd's miniatures; saw Carmen; Bay to England this morning; visited Billy Dodge's studio
Jan 24, 1899 - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subjects: Bay is the breadwinner; MacMonnies; R. Chanlers; Conkling's studio; met Redmond; Cecilia Beaux; Bob to Mr. Garnett's in S. C. with McKim; lunch for Alice Emmet
Jan 25, 1899 - To: Lydia - From: Mary G. Clarke (in Albany) - Subject: thanks for pin
[Feb 1899] - To: Lydia - From: L. B. Strong - Subject: Mary and Hyde
Feb 17, 1899 - To: Lydia - From: Leslie - Subjects: Matilda and Scudder; Mardi Gras; MacMonnies painting; Felix Faure died; party at Mrs. Lowell's (wife of architect); the von Hemerts
[May 1899] - To: Julia - From: Posie - Subjects: both Arthurs to Delhi; Bobby Sherwood
May 31, 1899 - To: Lydia - From: Emily Ladenburg - Subjects: picture of baby frame; Susy Wieling (?) and Miss Mason have studio
Jun 19, 1899 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: taught Southampton class; likes Elsie Griffiths; Lem Colt; (drawing of Queen of Hearts costume)
Jul 2, 1899 - To: Lydia (in U.S.) - From: Mary Foote - Subjects: Mary Thompson; Anita and Kob in Holland lastspring; Bay just back from England, now near Giverny; Saint-Gaudens admired Bay's portrait of Mrs. Crow, thought it a Sargent;MacMonnies baby due in August
Jul 4, 1899 - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subjects: Temple and Alida's new house
Jul 24, 1899 - To: Lydia - From: C.B. (?) - Subjects: McCulloughs liked portraits; C.B. (?) wants to do Bridgham portrait
Aug 16, [1899?] - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subject: J. P. Morgan's yacht
Oct 9, 1899 - To: Lydia - From: C.B. (?) - Subjects: Dewey's homecoming; Cecilia Beaux portrait of Dr. Huntington
Oct 13, 1899 - To: Lydia - From: Bay - Subjects: MacMonnies; Miss Foote; painting Stanley Clarke in London
Dec 20, 1899 - To: Posie - From: Henry James (in Rye, England) (transcript, fragment) - Subjects: answer to request for autograph; family activities
Dec 25, 1899 - To: Lydia - From: Bay - Subjects: Bobby Sherwood; Hyde Hall photos
Dec 28, 1899 - To: Posie - From: Henry James (in Rye, England) (transcript, fragment) - Subject: comments on Posie's article about Bay
Jan 13, 1900 - To: Posie - From: John Singer Sargent - Subject: thanks for the note about his picture
Jan 17, 1900 - To: Lydia - From: Rosina Hubley Emmet - Subjects: Sir Redvers Buller's opinion of the Boers; Stanley Clarke; Sargent liked Bay's portrait of Admiral Victor Montagu; the Choates; Rosina May paint George Hamilton; Prince of Wales; Bobby Cross
Jan 26, [1900] - To: Julia - From: Dev (in Ireland) - Subjects: activities in Dublin; South African war; Christopher La Touche, manager of Guinness Brewery
Feb 6, [1900] - To: Julia - From: Dev (County Galway, Ireland) - Subjects: sport shooting; Richard
[1900?] - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subject: Bay's visit; MacMonnies liked Bob and Robert
[circa Jul 1900] - To: Lydia - From: Posie (at Beech Hill, Westport, N.Y.) - Subjects: Ella to visit the Dewings in N.H.; Bob Emmet at Louvre and to Holland with Phillippe von Hemert; (drawing of Cynthia and Rosamond)
[circa Jul 1900] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: haven't seen E.G. Emmet's paintings yet; Rosina and Bay are studio hunting; Bay's stories of Henry James; Bay will paint Eleanor; Posie hesitant about going abroad
[circa Jul 1900] - To: Lydia - From: Bay (in U.S.) - Subjects: studio search; contacted wife of Gov. Smith
[circa Jul 1900] - To: Lydia - From: Posie (at Beech Hill, Westport, N.Y.) - Subjects: Lydia joining Posie on trip to Italy; Posie to visit Amsterdam and London; Posie painting Cynthia and Rosamond; Bay has rooms on first floor of Cecilia Beaux's studio
[circa Jul 1900] - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subjects: Bay has rooms in the Beaux studio house; Bessie Dufais in hospital after car accident with Louise
[circa Jul 1900] - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subjects: Bay's trunk did not come; will send slippers
[1900] - To: Lydia - From: Julia - Subjects: Posie won't go to Paris Exposition, then back to England; likes Julia Ward Howe's verses
Aug 18, 1900 - To: Julia - From: Julia Ward Howe - Subjects: thanks for liking verses; Margaret;collapse of the Chinese undertaking
[Fall 1900?] - To: ? - From: Henry James (in Rye, England) (transcript, fragment) - Subject: visits by family members
Aug 22,1900 - To: Bay - From: Henry James (in Rye, England) (transcript) -Subjects: Bay's departure; promises to look after her mother
Nov 14, 1900 - To: Julia - From: Mamy [sic] - Subjects: fancy dress for Cunard Gosling childrens' Xmas party; McKinley
[Dec 18, 1900] - To: Julia - From: Posie (aboard U.S.M.S. New York) - Subjects: Posie, Arthur Jr., Phil, Cynthia, and Aunty travel to Europe; met Miss Scudder and Mrs. Peabody
[Dec 1900] - To: Julia - From: Posie - Subject: travels in Germany
Jan 1, 1901 - To: Lydia - From: Posie (in Bockstadt) - Subjects: Xmas in Germany; (drawing of pointing hand)
Feb 21, 1901 - To: Julia - From: Posie - Subjects: Aunty and Posie to Dresden
Mar 3, 1901 - To: Jane - From: Posie (in Bockstadt) - Subject: Bay will paint Alty Morgan
Mar 10, 1901 - To: Dearest - From: Posie (in Rome) - Subjects: travels to Rouen, Switzerland, and Rome